Nancy Toppan Little Papers, 1914-1978
Smith College Archives
Nancy Toppan Little Papers
1914-1978
1914-1918
Little, Nancy Toppan.
RG 80. Class of 1918.
1 box (.49 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
Smith graduate. Contains correspondence from Smith, memorabilia book, class songs, programs, and memoirs of college reunions.
Nancy Toppan Little, class of 1918, lived her entire life in Newburyport, Massachusetts. During her four years at Smith she studied Math, English, German, History, Latin, Biblical Literature, Geology, Philosophy, Physics, Economics and Physical Education and was a member of the Math Club. She also taught classes in Arithmetic and Geography at the People's Institute of Northampton. Between her graduation and her marriage on June 16, 1920 to Herbert Greenleaf Noyes, also of Newburyport, she worked briefly as a bank clerk. Her sixty-one-year marriage produced three sons, nine grandchildren and many great-grandchildren. Until her death in 1995, Little delighted in outdoor walks and visits from her large family.
The Nancy Toppan Little Papers contain correspondence to her family from her enrollment at Smith College in 1914 until her graduation in 1918. The papers also contain materials relating to her college career, including a memorabilia book, class songs, programs from Smith theatrical events, and memoirs of her 45th and 60th college reunions.
This collection is organized into four series:
I. Correspondence
II. Photographs and Memorabilia Book
III. Smith Materials
IV. Post-Smith Materials
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
Search Terms
Little, Nancy Toppan.; Smith College--Students.
Additional Information
Related Material
80. Class of 1918 Records
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1918
  This series is comprised primarily of Little's letters to her parents and sister during the four years she studied at Smith College. Her letters mostly deal with daily life at Smith, such as academic work, sports, theatre, activities with friends, food, clothing, requests for money, and gentlemen callers, as well as glee and mandolin club concerts. She also writes about general life in Haven House, including freshman pranks, tea, and other social gatherings. There are also several telegrams that she received, and also a letter from the Office of the Physician about precautionary measures taken in response to the epidemic of Infantile Paralysis in 1916.
  - Correspondence Sept 1914 - Dec 1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Jan 1915 - June 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Sept 1915 - Dec 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Jan 1916 - June 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Sept 1916 - Dec 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Jan 1917 - June 1917 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Sept 1917 - Dec 1917 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Jan 1918 - June 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- SERIES II. PHOTOGRAPHS AND MEMORABILIA BOOK
  Little's memorabilia book ranges from 1914 to 1918 containing articles pertianing mainly to Smith College, although several mention her specifically. Also included in the series are three photographs of Little during her college career.
  - Memorabilia Book 1914 - 18 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- SERIES III. SMITH MATERIALS
  This series consists of miscellaneous materials that pertain to her Smith career. These include invitations to athletic events, notes to her, People's Institute papers, copies of class songs, as well as dance and report cards.
  - Athletic Invitations 1916 - 18 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class Songs 1915, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Concert Programs 1915 - 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notes to Nancy Little 1914, 1915, 1916, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - People's Institute 1915-16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Play Bills 1915- 18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Report Cards 1914 -18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- SERIES IV. POST-SMITH MATERIALS
  This series consists primarily of concert programs and playbills of events Little after her graduation from Smith in 1918. Also included in the series are memoirs of her 45th and 60th college reunions.
  - Notes 1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Play Bills 1919, 1920, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Reunion Materials 1963, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)